[Music]
[Applause]
this
is the tavo world tour we are being
joined by
20 medical teams from 20 different
centers
to create awareness and fight heart
disease i'm dr rahul sharma dr
eberhard from the heart valve center
india from heart center and najaf iraq
from the
royal brotherhood hospital in london
world tour
[Music]
this world heart day these 20 surgical
teams performed the advanced
tower wall replacement surgery
simultaneously to spread awareness
that serious heart ailments are deadlier
than kobit 19
and need immediate care the global
platform
was geomet
heart disease continues to be the major
killer in spite of kovet
in terms of mortality and morbidity
so if let's say we have 100 patients
uh you know 50 how all have significant
heart disease
and 50 have coveted the chances of
patients with heart disease succumbing
to
harm is more than the chance of co with
patients coming to harm this is a
worldwide fact
thing i'd like to uh um convey to uh
people and the patients
that if they do need heart treatment
they need to get out there and get help
and that's the whole idea of this
massive worldwide campaign
the initiative by the heart team india
brought the spotlight to minimally
invasive
transcatheter iotic wall replacement
procedures
that offer faster recovery and a safer
alternative to conventional open heart
surgeries
the least invasive procedures appears to
be
the best for the patients in terms of
getting them out of hospital
as soon as possible helping them with
media recovery
and the result indirectly minimizes the
risk of
infection with corvette because
dimensional open heart surgery in an
elderly man
usually takes uh about a week 10 days in
hospital
and a rehabilitation of about four weeks
now you you've just seen in the screen
we replace the valves
of elderly people within 30 minutes
about 20 valves across the world were
replaced
and most of these patients are going to
be walking home next year the day after
terror world tour made a record in
medical history and was watched by
millions
capturing the spirit of one team one
heart
in mumbai